

MUGAMBI KELVIN KIMATHI

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST | DATABASE ADMIN

OVERVIEW

Born in Aug, 1996, I am a project manager and network associate with 3 years' experience in software and web development using technologies like Laravel PHP framework, MySQL database and statistical data analysis in python in different libraries.

SKILLS

Programming and web development

(Front end web development, PHP, MySQL database, PostgreSQL, Python Django framework, SQL Server)

Project Management

EXPERIENCE

ICT SUPPORT • FLAMINGO HORTICULTURE LTD • (JAN 2021 TO DEC 2021)

Provide necessary IT support throughout the company

Duties

- Installation and configuration of company's computer hardware, operating systems upgrades and applications' testing.
- Installation, maintenance and monitoring of computer network systems
- System and software audits
- Biometric systems management and scheduling of backups
- Diagnosing and fixing software and hardware issues
- Android devices configurations and setup for wireless access in company's intranet

WEB DEVELOPER • ARKESSAYS • SEP 2019 - DEC 2020

Lead in the design and development of arkwrittingservices.com website. Others include WordPress development and host management of https://www.ultratrade.com/

(Smartsheet, MS Project)

Computer networks

(Cisco CCNA 1, CCNA 2, CCNA 3 & CCNA 4)

Reporting and Collaboration

Git, Bitbucket

Cloud

Microsoft Azure, AWS

Computer Security

(CCNA Security, Firewall setups)

Critical Thinking

Duties

- Design and development following the SDLC convention for software development
- Database design and integration to frontend web design for data store
- Web hosting and ensuring of secure web access across all devices
- Performance testing, SEO and SEM

INDUSTRIAL ATTACHMENT • ELEARNING MASENO UNIVERSITY(KISUMU) • MAY 2019 – AUG 2019

I underwent a 4-month industrial attachment at the university of Maseno (*Kisumu campus*) where i was able to perform the following.

Duties

- Computer and networking systems maintenance and upgrades
- IT support and troubleshooting
- Performing hardware audits and upgrades
- Backend web development in php and MySQL
- Front end and web design in HTML and CSS and bootstrap (online staff leave application portal)
- Data entry and analysis
- Installation of CCTV cameras and footage storage

EDUCATION

DEGREE • 2015 TO 2020 • MASENO UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (IT)

KCSE • 2011 - 2014 • KANGARU SCHOOL

Attained Grade A- aggregate.

ACHIEVEMENTS

SACCO MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEM

During my last year of study, I worked on digitization of various Sacco and small self-help groups to develop an online application.

The system received applauses from the IT Project assessment panel during the final presentation and several Sacco societies I visited for showcasing.

COMPLETE SCHOOL MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE

During my third year in school, I worked with a few other classmates in the development of a multipurpose school management software that enables schools to automate all its operations including student admissions, fee management, exam results processing, library management and records systems.

The demo can be found at https://ideal.codeisystems.co.ke

Example of some of the schools using the system include:

- Keveye girls' secondary school https://keveyeschool.sc.ke
- 2. Eden cottage primary school (Offline mode)

PERSONALITY

Time management

- Problem solver and rapid adaptability
- Team player
- Good communication skills
- Initiative
- Organization
- Empathetic

HOBBIES

- √ Playing chess
- √ Adventuring
- √ Football
- ✓ Charity work

CONTACTS

Email: kelvinkimathi365@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelvin-kimathi-

812a45106/

GitHub: https://github.com/kelvincheskimzion

Mobile: 0717-966-805 | 0111-339-796

WhatsApp: +254757827116

REFEREES

Doreen Kawira Riungu

Assistant Stores Foreman,

Procurement Procedures,

Flamingo Horticulture Ltd 0723 425 020

Kawira.doreen@flamingo.net

James Chamwama
Chairperson IT department,
Maseno University
0722 399 874

chamwama@maseno.ac.ke

Michael Opiyo
eCampus Maseno
University (Kisumu) Supervisor,
0722 311 597
mzopiyoh@gmail.com